MOHAMED THAKIR NIYAS RAHUMAN

SKILLS

React js

Typescript

Javascript

HTML CSS

Devops

GIT

LANGUAGES

English

Proficient



Native

CERTIFICATE

GCP (Associate Cloud Engineer), Google Cloud

02/2022 - 08/2022

AWS (Cloud Partiticioner)

04/2023 - 11/2023

Front End Developer

wtm_source=share&utm_campaign=share_via&utm_content=profile&utm_medium=android_app

app

app

outm_source=share&utm_campaign=share_via&utm_content=profile&utm_medium=android_app

outm_source=share&utm_campaign=share_via&utm_content=profile&utm_medium=android_app

outm_source=share&utm_campaign=share_via&utm_content=profile&utm_medium=android_app

outm_source=share&utm_sourc

Chennai

SUMMARY

Accomplished Software Developer with over 2+ years of developing and implementing responsive websites. Expertise in React JS, Typescript, Javascript, HTML, CSS, and other programming languages. I have a deep understanding of web technologies, user interface design principles, and a strong passion for creating intuitive and visually appealing websites.

EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer

02/2022 - Present

Tata Consultancy Services

Chennai

Client: Lloyds Bank PLC

Worked as a team of developers to successfully complete a major software project on time and within budget

Working on typescript react based applications and also have migrated javascript project into typescript

Refactored existing code to improve readability and maintainability, resulting in a 40% reduction in development time

Built modular and reusable components to reduce code duplication and ease future maintenance with a focus on content management.

Optimised the application for performance, resulting in a 15% reduction in loading time

Developed and deployed APIs to integrate the front-end application with backend services

Created a Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) pipeline that reduced time-to-deployment from days to hours

Interfaced with clients to identify business requirements to decide on the technical specifications of projects

Continually engaged in emerging technology research and development

Coordinated with design leads, architects, product owners and other key stakeholders to improve existing application and code creative solutions using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React.

Trade Apprenticeship

08/2021 - 02/2022

NLC India PVT LTD

Neyveli

EDUCATION

MCA 07/2019 - 07/2021

Crescent University

BSC(Computer science)

08/2016 - 06/2019

Aditanar college of Arts and science